Mss.Rec.193 Mss.Rec.193
American Philosophical Society
Potawatomi language recordings
1992
Mss.Rec.193
American Philosophical Society
16.0 Tape(s)
16 sound cassettes (18 hr., 4 min.): analog, 1 7/8 ips, stereo.
Buszard-Welcher, Laura
Wesaw, Julia
Wesaw, Martin
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Laura Buszard-Welcher in 1995 (Acc. 1995-144r). This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Basket making; Berries--Harvesting; Maple syrup; Potawatomi Indians--Domestic life; Potawatomi Indians--Education; Potawatomi Indians--Social life and customs; Potawatomi language; Potawatomi language--Acquisition; Potawatomi language--Study and teaching; Pottery craft; Sound recordings; United States. Navy.; World War, 1939-1945
- Audio recordings
  - Potawatomi language class, 1992-07-01; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:44:48; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Julia; Wesaw, Martin
    Scope and Contents note
    Potawatomi language class held at the College of the Potawatomi Center taught by Julia Wesaw and Martin Wesaw. Small informal group. Vocabulary drills. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 1, program 1. Formerly numbered 1:1.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Audiocassette) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Dowagiac (Mich.); Potawatomi language; Potawatomi language--Study and teaching
  - Potawatomi language class, 1992-07-01; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:45:01; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Julia; Wesaw, Martin
    Potawatomi language class held at the College of the Potawatomi Center taught by Julia Wesaw and Martin Wesaw. Small informal group. Vocabulary drills. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 1, program 2. Formerly numbered 2:1.
  - Interview with Julia & John Wesaw, 1992-07-06; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:43; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, John; Wesaw, Julia
    Conversation in English about berry picking, boarding school, and speaking Potawatomi. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 2, program 1. Formerly numbered 2:2.
    Berries--Harvesting; Hartford (Mich.); Potawatomi Indians--Education; Potawatomi Indians--Social life and customs; Potawatomi language
  - Interview with Julia & John Wesaw, 1992-07-06; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:34; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, John; Wesaw, Julia
    Conversation in English about racial discrimination, personal stories, berry picking, and baskets. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 2, program 2. Formerly numbered 3:1.
    Basket making; Berries--Harvesting; Hartford (Mich.); Potawatomi Indians--Social life and customs; Race discrimination
  - Interview with Julia Wesaw & Ella Louis, 1992-07-07; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:26:21; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Louis, Ella; Wesaw, Julia
    Discussion of speaking and learning Potawatomi. Discussion and elicitation of words for the seasons, birds and animals, times of the day, and weather. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 3, program 1. Formerly numbered 3:2.
    Hartford (Mich.); Potawatomi Indians--Social life and customs; Potawatomi language; Potawatomi language--Acquisition
  - Interview with Julia Wesaw & Ella Louis, 1992-07-07; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:50; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Louis, Ella; Wesaw, Julia
    Elicitation of miscellaneous Potawatomi words and phrases, as well as words for animals, birds, and household items. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 3, program 2. Formerly numbered 3:3.
    Hartford (Mich.); Potawatomi language
  - Interview with Julia Wesaw & Ella Louis, 1992-07-07; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:01; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Louis, Ella; Wesaw, Julia
    Discussion of basket making. Elicitation of Potawatomi words for colors, animals, and parts of the body. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 3, program 3. Formerly numbered 4:1.
    Basket making; Hartford (Mich.); Potawatomi Indians--Social life and customs; Potawatomi language
  - Interview with Julia Wesaw & Ella Louis, 1992-07-07; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:25:01; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Louis, Ella; Wesaw, Julia
    Elicitation of Potawatomi words for animals, food, money, parts of the body, and miscellaneous terms, followed by general discussion. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 3, program 4. Formerly numbered 4:2.
    Hartford (Mich.); Potawatomi Indians--Social life and customs; Potawatomi language
  - Interview with Julia Wesaw on the making of Black Ash baskets, 1992-07; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:27; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Julia
    General conversation and description of basket-making, including some Potawatomi vocabulary. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 4, program 1. Formerly numbered 4:3.
  - Interview with Julia Wesaw on the making of Black Ash baskets, 1992-07; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:21:50; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Julia
    Conversation in English about basket making while consultant makes a basket, with other conversation on cooking turtle, other animals, and pottery making. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 4, program 2. Formerly numbered 5:1.
    Basket making; Hartford (Mich.); Potawatomi Indians--Social life and customs; Pottery craft
  - Interview with Julia Wesaw, 1992-07; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:45; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Julia
    Informal interview conducted while consultant made baskets. TV in background. Many long pauses. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 4, program 3. Formerly numbered 5:2.
    Basket making; Hartford (Mich.); Potawatomi Indians
  - Interview with Julia Wesaw, 1992-07; 06-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:02; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Julia
    Informal interview conducted while consultant made baskets. TV in background. Many long pauses. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 4, program 4. Formerly numbered 5:3.
  - Interview with Julia Wesaw reading words and phrases from Daniels' text, 1992-07; 07-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:43:45; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Julia
    Interview with readings and elicitations from B. Daniels, et al., eds., "Potawatomi Language Manual, Resource Materials and Training Exercises" (Milwaukee: Great Lakes Inter-Tribal Council, Inc., University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee, 1976) Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 5, program 1. Formerly numbered 6:1.
    Basket making; Hartford (Mich.); Ottawa language; Potawatomi language
  - Interview with Julia Wesaw reading words and phrases from Daniels' text, 1992-07; 07-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:32:31; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Julia
    Interview with readings and elicitations from B. Daniels, et al., eds., "Potawatomi Language Manual, Resource Materials and Training Exercises" (Milwaukee: Great Lakes Inter-Tribal Council, Inc., University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee, 1976) Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 5, program 2. Formerly numbered 6:2.
  - Interview with Martin Wesaw, 1992-07; 08-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:43:19; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Martin
    Discussion followed by the text "When I was young" about childhood and personal history given in Potawatomi and English. Elicitation of numbers. Discussion of Potawatomi speakers. Elicitation of verb paradigms for 'walk,' 'to be red,' and 'hit.' Discussion of making maple syrup. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 6, program 1. Formerly numbered 7:1.
    Maple syrup; Michigan; Potawatomi Indians; Potawatomi language
  - Interview with Martin Wesaw, 1992-07; 08-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:38; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Martin
    Interview, with the text "Making Maple Syrup" given in English. Conversation in English on consultant's personal history, a tornado, and selling baskets. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 6, program 2. Formerly numbered 7:2.
  - Interview with Martin Wesaw, 1992-07; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:44:12; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Martin
    Interview, with text "Making Maple Syrup" given in Potawatomi, conversation on picking blueberries, and miscellaneous elicited vocabulary. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 7, program 1. Formerly numbered 8:1.
    Blueberries; Hartford (Mich.); Maple syrup; Potawatomi Indians; Potawatomi language
  - Interview with Martin Wesaw, 1992-07; 09-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:40:13; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Martin
    Elicitation of Potawatomi words for fruits, vegetables, animals, trees, followed by verb paradigms for 'hit.' Includes general conversation and analysis of earlier text, "When I was young." Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 7, program 2. Formerly numbered 9:1.
  - Interview with Martin Wesaw, 1992-07; 10-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:42:41; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Martin
    Discussion of hunting and elicitation of related Potawatomi words. Conversation about berry-picking, followed by story about huckleberries. Ends with elicitation of verb paradigms for 'hit.' Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 8, program 1. Formerly numbered 10:1.
    Berries--Harvesting; Hartford (Mich.); Huckleberries; Hunting; Potawatomi Indians; Potawatomi language
  - Interview with Martin Wesaw, 1992-07; 10-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:54; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Martin
    Elicitation of Potawatomi verb paradigms for 'hit.' Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 8, program 2. Formerly numbered 10:2.
  - Interview with Martin Wesaw, 1992-07; 11-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:43:32; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Martin
    Interview, including text "Going to school" given in Potawatomi and English, story about being in the Navy in World War II, and discussion of life after being in the service. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 9, program 1. Formerly numbered 11:1.
    Hartford (Mich.); Potawatomi Indians--Education; Potawatomi language; United States. Navy.; World War, 1939-1945
  - Interview with Martin Wesaw, 1992-07; 11-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:40:58; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Martin
    Recollections in English, elicitations of Potawatomi verb paradigms for "walk," "hit," and "to be round," with general English conversation. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 9, program 2. Formerly numbered 12:1.
  - Interview and elicitations with Julia Wesaw, 1992-07-27; 12-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:36:46; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Julia
    Elicitation of Potawatomi questions, variations of "go," seasons, and negated sentences, with general conversation. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 10, program 1. Formerly numbered 12:2.
  - Interview, texts, and elicitations with Martin Wesaw, 1992-07-27; 12-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:43:27; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Martin
    Elicitation of Potawatomi sentences, words for directions, and review of material from earlier text, "Going to school." Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 11, program 1. Formerly numbered 13:1.
  - Interview, texts, and elicitations with Martin Wesaw, 1992-07; 13-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:43:36; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Martin
    Elicitation of miscellaneous Potawatomi vocabulary, discussion of old sayings, conversation about granddaughter, texts "Barney Google" and "Sorehead" given in Potawatomi and English, and "Getting lost" in English. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 11, program 2. Formerly numbered 14:1.
    Granddaughters; Hartford (Mich.); Potawatomi Indians; Potawatomi language
  - Interview and elicitations with Julia Wesaw, 1992-07-29; 13-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:42:42; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Julia
    Elicitation of Potawatomi verbs and terms for clothing and household items. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 12, program 1. Formerly numbered 15:1.
    Clothing and dress; Hartford (Mich.); Potawatomi Indians--Domestic life; Potawatomi language
  - Interview and elicitations with Julia Wesaw, 1992-07-29; 14-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:40:09; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Julia
    Elicitation of Potawatomi verbs and adjectives. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 12, program 2. Formerly numbered 16:1.
  - Interview and elicitations with Julia Wesaw, 1992-07-29; 14-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:43:01; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Julia
    Elicitation of Potawatomi words and phrases, primarily verbs, with terms for birds and clothing. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 13, program 1. Formerly numbered 17:1.
    Birds; Clothing and dress; Hartford (Mich.); Potawatomi language
  - Interview and elicitations with Julia Wesaw, 1992-07-29; 15-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:27:19; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Julia
    Elicitation of Potawatomi words and phrases. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 13, program 2. Formerly numbered 17:2.
  - Interview with Martin Wesaw, 1992-07; 15-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:43:28; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Martin
    Interview, with the text "Setting traps" given in Potawatomi and English, and "Getting lost" in Potawatomi. Conversation on growing fruits and vegetables. Elicitation of Potawatomi words related to fishing. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 14, program 1. Formerly numbered 18:1.
    Fishing; Fruits; Hartford (Mich.); Potawatomi language; Trapping; Vegetable gardening
  - Interview and elicitations with Martin Wesaw, 1992-07; 16-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:40:01; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Martin
    Elicitation of Potawatomi words and phrases, primarily verbs and terms for clothing. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 14, program 2. Formerly numbered 19:1.
    Clothing and dress; Hartford (Mich.); Potawatomi language
  - Interview and elicitations with Martin Wesaw, 1992-07; 16-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:34:53; Buszard-Welcher, Laura A.; Wesaw, Martin
    Elicitation of Potawatomi verb paradigms for "hit," "see," and "cry." Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. Original tape 15, program 1. Formerly numbered 19:2.